{
    "id": "2bb88c1bbcc34de9b518dea863508be5",
    "title": "Prepositions After Verbs, Nouns, And Adjectives",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "6fb35ee516c7415199e2409accd93819",
            "title": "Prepositions After Verbs, Nouns And Adjectives",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "I am interested ...................... learning to fly.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "in",
                        "on",
                        "at",
                        "for"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "John's criticism ......................... the plan made him unpopular.",
                    "description": "The noun criticism needs a preposition to connect it to a noun or ing form. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "of",
                        "about"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He has always been critical ......................... me.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "with",
                        "of",
                        "about"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I resent .................................. on weekends.",
                    "description": "Some verbs can be followed by nouns or ing forms with no preposition. Resent is one of them. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "working",
                        "for working",
                        "about working"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "My resentment .................................. working on holidays made me unpopular with my boss.",
                    "description": "Resentment is followed by of. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "of",
                        "for",
                        "with"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I feel resentful ......................... working on Sundays.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "of",
                        "about"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She ignored our worries ........................... her health.",
                    "description": "We worry about something. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "of",
                        "about",
                        "for"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I can only sympathize ......................... you.",
                    "description": "We sympathize with people. We do not sympathize for or at them. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "with",
                        "at"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I feel great sympathy ........................ her.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "with",
                        "at",
                        "for",
                        "about"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I feel sympathetic ............................. the poor.",
                    "description": "Sympathetic is followed by towards. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "with",
                        "at",
                        "towards"
                    ],
                    "correct": 3
                },
                {
                    "question": "I had given up hope ........................ seeing her again.",
                    "description": "Hope is followed by of + noun/ing form. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "for",
                        "to",
                        "of"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She ....................... the station last night.",
                    "description": "A preposition is usually necessary before an expression of place. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "arrived",
                        "arrived at",
                        "arrived to"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}